A Register of the Agnes M. Diterichs Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Agnes M. Diterichs Papers
1919-1922
2008C78
Diterichs, Agnes M., collector.
2 microfilm reel (0.3 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
These papers contain the detailed investigative report of the assassination of the last Tsar of Russia, Nicholas II, and his family. The report was prepared by Nikolai Alekseevich Sokolov, and includes the typescript of "Dielo ob ubiestvie tsarskoi sem'i v Ekaterinburgie," and related documents, including correspondence, illustrations, and minutes.
Administrative Information
Access
The collection is open for research
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by Hoover Institution Archives in 2008
Alternative Forms of Material Available
Full collection is available on Microfilm
Location of Originals
In part, Holy Trinity Orthodox Seminary, Jordanville, New York
Scope and Content of Collection
These papers contain the detailed investigative report of the assassination of the last Tsar of Russia, Nicholas II, and his family. The report was prepared by Nikolai Alekseevich Sokolov, and includes the typescript of "Dielo ob ubiestvie tsarskoi sem'i v Ekaterinburgie," and related documents, including correspondence, illustrations, and minutes. Also included is P. A. Severnyi's unpublished manuscript "Poslednie dni imperatora Nikolaia vtorogo."
Detailed processing and preservation microfilming for these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and the Holy Trinity Seminary. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials remain in the Holy Trinity Seminary Archives as its property. A transfer table indicating corresponding box and reel numbers is appended to this register. Any views, findings, conclusions or recommendations expressed in these materials do not necessarily represent those of the National Endowment for the Humanities.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into two series: Sokolov Commission Investigation file, and Writings by others
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the online catalog.
Subjects
Sokolov, Nikolai. Ubiistvo tsarskoi sem'i.; Nicholas II, Emperor of Russia 1868-1918--Assassination.; Photographs.
Container List
- Sokolov Commission Investigation file, 1919-1922. (Box 1)
  Correspondence, clipping, illustrations and photographs, map, typescript of "Dielo ob ubiistvie tsarskoi sem'i v Ekaterinburge," inventory, minutes, and notes
  - Correspondence
    - General, 1919 and undated (Folder 1: 1)
    - Vostrotin, Stepan Vasil'evich, 1922 (Folder 1: 2)
  - "Dielo ob ubiistvie tsarskoi sem'i v Ekaterinburgie,", 1918
    - Clipping, undated (Folder 1: 3)
    - Illustrations and photographs (113 prints), numbered. (Folder 1: 4)
      Includes descriptions of each image
    - Map, Ekaterinburg uezd, hand colored, 1919 (Folder 1: 5)
    - Typescript (Folder 1: 6-9)
  - Inventory, undated (Folder 1: 10)
  - Minutes, 1919 and undated (Folder 1: 11)
  - Notes, undated (Folder 1: 12)
- Writings by others., 1921-1922
  - Severnyi, Pavel A., "Poslednie dni Imperatora Nikolaia vtorogo," play, 1921-1922. (Folder 1: 13)
    Holograph